export const INFOCOMMTECHA2015 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The number of characters that ASCII-8 coding system scheme represents is",
A: "8",
B: "16",
C: "36",
D: "256",
answer: "D. 256",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. The binary equivalence of the decimal number 17 is",
A: "11112",
B: "11102",
C: "110002",
D: "100012",
answer: "B. 11102",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The following are examples of utility programs except",
A: "editors",
B: "file maintenance",
C: "operating systems",
D: "tracing and debugging",
answer: "C. operating systems",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The tile between job submission and the return of results in batch processing is known as",
A: "elapsed time",
B: "job around time",
C: "turnaround time",
D: "return around time",
answer: "C. turnaround time",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of the following is not a component of a decision support system?",
A: "Corporate database",
B: "Decision database",
C: "Model database",
D: "Planning language",
answer: "D. Planning language",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following is not an attribute of useful information?",
A: "Accurate",
B: "Neat",
C: "Precise",
D: "Reliable",
answer: "B. Neat",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The software that is used to arrange text and graphics into professional-looking document is called",
A: "image editors",
B: "spreadsheet programs",
C: "desktop publishing programs",
D: "database management programs",
answer: "C. desktop publishing programs",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. Which of the following is not an example of desktop publishing application?",
A: "Adobe PageMaker",
B: "Adobe Reader",
C: "MS Publisher",
D: "QuarkXPress",
answer: "B. Adobe Reader",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. To select multiple non-adjacent cells in a worksheet, click on the cells while holding down the",
A: "ALT key",
B: "CTRL key",
C: "CTRL+ALT keys",
D: "SHIFT key",
answer: "D. SHIFT key",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Which of the following displays the content of an active cell in a worksheet?",
A: "Formula bar",
B: "Menu bar",
C: "Name box",
D: "Status bar",
answer: "A. Formula bar",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The process of identifying specific rows and columns so that these rows and columns are always visible on the screen is called",
A: "fixing",
B: "freezing",
C: "locking",
D: "selecting",
answer: "B. freezing",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The default paper size in the ISO’s A series is",
A: "A0",
B: "A3",
C: "A4",
D: "A10",
answer: "C. A4",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. In a spreadsheet, which of the following is a text function?",
A: "COUNT()",
B: "DMAX()",
C: "ROUND()",
D: "UPPER()",
answer: "D. UPPER()",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. A red triangle at the top right corner of a cell in a spreadsheet program indicates that",
A: "the value in the cell is incorrect",
B: "the cell cannot accept formula",
C: "there is a comment associated with the cell",
D: "the formula entered into the cell has an error",
answer: "C. there is a comment associated with the cell",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Which of the following memories is typically upgraded on a computer?",
A: "DRAM",
B: "QRAM",
C: "SRAM",
D: "VRAM",
answer: "A. DRAM",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which ends of a SCSI bus should be terminated?",
A: "Both ends of the chain",
B: "Neither end",
C: "Only the end of the chain",
D: "The beginning to f the chain",
answer: "C. Only the end of the chain",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which type of the bus architecture supports 64-bit and 32-bit data paths?",
A: "EISA",
B: "ISA",
C: "PCI",
D: "VESA",
answer: "C. PCI",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. A device used within the computer that conducts and draws heat away from the processor is called?",
A: "radiator",
B: "thermostat",
C: "heat sink",
D: "air conditioner",
answer: "C. heat sink",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following can be found on the motherboard?",
A: "BIOS chip",
B: "CMOS battery",
C: "Hard disk drive",
D: "Underlying circuitry",
answer: "A. BIOS chip",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Which of the following power voltages goes to the ground?",
A: "+5 volts DC",
B: "-5 volts DC",
C: "+12 volts DC",
D: "-12 volts DC",
answer: "B. -5 volts DC",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The feature that allows a device to distract the CPU for a moment, take control of the bus, and read from or write information to the device is known as bus",
A: "capturing",
B: "controlling",
C: "distraction",
D: "mastering",
answer: "D. mastering",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following is true of customized software?",
A: "They are inexpensive",
B: "They are not fully documented",
C: "They meet the exact needs of the user",
D: "They are designed to meet the needs of many different uses",
answer: "C. They meet the exact needs of the user",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Application software interacts with the computer through the",
A: "linker",
B: "translator",
C: "system software",
D: "user interface.",
answer: "D. user interface.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The process of reducing the size of data on a disk in order to save space can be carried out by",
A: "scanning the disk",
B: "compressing data on the disk",
C: "applying antivirus software",
D: "deleting the data on the disk",
answer: "B. compressing data on the disk",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. Which of the following is not an example of utility program?",
A: "File copying",
B: "File organization",
C: "File sourcing",
D: "Merge routing",
answer: "C. File sourcing",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Which of the following is not a characteristic of off-the-shelf software?",
A: "They are inexpensive",
B: "They are fully documented",
C: "They meet the exact needs of the user",
D: "They are designed to meet the needs of many different users",
answer: "C. They meet the exact needs of the user",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Every operating system must be able to perform the following functions except",
A: "control resources",
B: "reclaim resources",
C: "distribute resources",
D: "put resources into use",
answer: "C. distribute resources",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. One of the characteristics of machine language is that",
A: "it uses mnemonic code",
B: "each computer has its own machine language",
C: "it uses simple words that are easy to remember",
D: "it uses complex words that are difficult to remember",
answer: "B. each computer has its own machine language",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The first compiled programming language was",
A: "C++",
B: "FORTRAN",
C: "Pascal",
D: "Visual Basic",
answer: "B. FORTRAN",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following HTML tags displays the name of the page in the caption bar of a browser?",
A: "<link>",
B: "<meta>",
C: "<style>",
D: "<title>",
answer: "D. <title>",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The HTML tag <table width=”500”> means",
A: "500mm wide",
B: "500cm wide",
C: "500 words",
D: "500 pixel wide",
answer: "D. 500 pixel wide",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. The create a hyperlink in HTML, use",
A: "<a href=http://www.waecgh.org></a>",
B: "<b href=http://www.waecgh.org></b>",
C: "<c href=http://www.waecgh.org></c>",
D: "<d href=http://www.waecgh.org></d>",
answer: "A. <a href=http://www.waecgh.org></a>",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following HTML tags is valid?",
A: "<h1>WAEC Ghana<h1/>",
B: "<b1>WAEC Ghana</b1>",
C: "<u>WAEC Ghana</u>",
D: "<u><b>WAEC Ghana</u></b>",
answer: "A. <h1>WAEC Ghana<h1/>",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The <img> tag in a web page is used to",
A: "create an image",
B: "display an image",
C: "print an image",
D: "display only jpeg images",
answer: "B. display an image",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. To create a cell in an HTML table, use the tag",
A: "<body>…</body>",
B: "<td>…</td>",
C: "<th>…</th>",
D: "<tr>…</tr>",
answer: "B. <td>…</td>",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The form of data transmission that sends a start signal, followed by a group of message bits for a character of data, followed by a stop signal is called",
A: "asynchronous",
B: "character based",
C: "multiplexing",
D: "synchronous",
answer: "A. asynchronous",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Local area networks are intended to: \nI. Restrict physical movement of personnel\nII. Share programs among connected computers.\nIII. Share data among connected computers\nIV. Share peripheral devices among connected computers",
A: "I and II only",
B: "II and III only",
C: "III and IV only",
D: "I, II, III and IV",
answer: "B. II and III only",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The language used in authoring web pages is called",
A: "BASIC",
B: "C++",
C: "HTML",
D: "JAVA",
answer: "C. HTML",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following is the same as http://127.0.0.1 in the address bar of a web client?",
A: "http://hostip",
B: "http://local",
C: "http://localhost",
D: "http://www.local.com",
answer: "C. http://localhost",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Which of the following is not a factor to be considered when selecting network type for an organization to implement?",
A: "Size of the organization",
B: "Amount of network traffic",
C: "Location of the organization",
D: "Level of administrative support available",
answer: "C. Location of the organization",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. In the OSI model, repeaters operate at the",
A: "data link layer",
B: "network layer",
C: "physical layer",
D: "transport layer",
answer: "C. physical layer",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Which of the following cables transmit data at the least speed?",
A: "Category 2 UTP",
B: "Category 3 UTP",
C: "Category 4 UTP",
D: "Category 5 UTP",
answer: "A. Category 2 UTP",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The cable that is best suitable for implementing a bus topology is",
A: "coaxial",
B: "fiber optic",
C: "shielded twisted pair",
D: "unshielded twisted pair",
answer: "A. coaxial",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The following are date types except",
A: "date",
B: "field",
C: "number",
D: "text",
answer: "B. field",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Which of the following is a valid field name?",
A: "First/name",
B: "First&name",
C: "Firstname%",
D: "Firstname",
answer: "D. _Firstname",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. The code that is stored with a form or report is called",
A: "class module",
B: "form module",
C: "general module",
D: "standard module",
answer: "B. form module",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. What will the following SQL syntax do: \nSELECT fieldlist\nFROM tablename\nIN anotherdatabase.mdb\nWHERE condition\nGROUP BY fieldlist\nHAVING conditions for fields that are grouped\nORDERED BY fieldlist.",
A: "Add records to a table",
B: "Update records for fields that are grouped",
C: "Make a table from resulting values",
D: "Selecting data from one or more tables and displaying result",
answer: "D. Selecting data from one or more tables and displaying result",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The row selection buttons on a datasheet are located in the",
A: "field selection area",
B: "row selection area",
C: "record selection area",
D: "table selection area",
answer: "B. row selection area",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The maximum length of a text field in a database is",
A: "75",
B: "120",
C: "255",
D: "265",
answer: "C. 255",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The technology that presents information in more than one medium including text, graphics, animations, video, music and voice is known as",
A: "computer animation",
B: "computer graphics",
C: "multimedia",
D: "multiplexing",
answer: "C. multimedia",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]